  <page>
    <title>Talk:July 2005 United Nations assault on Cité Soleil</title>
    <id>2425001</id>
    <revision>
      <id>166823616</id>
      <timestamp>2007-10-24T20:23:16Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>SineBot</username>
        <id>4936590</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor />
      <comment>Signing comment by [[User:68.227.185.187|68.227.185.187]] - &quot;/* Background info needed */&quot;</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{WikiProject Caribbean |class=B |importance=Mid }}

==Background info needed==

This is a clearly biased statement with little (or no) substantiating evidence.  The language is also clearly not objective, using words like &quot;slaughter&quot; and &quot;assault&quot;  It reflects poorly on Wikipedia to have such an article present.  I suggest it be removed immediately until it is revised or substantiated by better evidence.  &lt;small&gt;—Preceding [[Wikipedia:Signatures|unsigned]] comment added by [[Special:Contributions/68.227.185.187|68.227.185.187]] ([[User talk:68.227.185.187|talk]]) 20:21, 24 October 2007 (UTC)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;!-- Template:UnsignedIP --&gt; &lt;!--Autosigned by SineBot--&gt;

The possible motivation for the UN troops to engage in a massacre needs to be addressed.  I believe the UN troops have been attacked in the past.  If they thought the perpetrators were in the area, that could explain their actions.  The nationalities  of UN troops involved should also be given, along with links to stories on past UN clashes in Haiti. [[User:StuRat|StuRat]] 23:45, 10 August 2005 (UTC)

==Inconsistency==

To me the term &quot;massacre&quot; is inconsistent with casualties in the 50 range in such a densely populated area, where I would expect thousands of people to live.  Such a low proportion of dead and wounded implies that the UN did attempt to limit collateral damage in their search for enemies.  The population of the area which was sealed off is definitely an important fact that should be included in the article. [[User:StuRat|StuRat]] 23:45, 10 August 2005 (UTC)

== Bias ==

Much more material is given from the anti-UN point of view than in support of UN activities in Haiti.  Links to articles discussing the level of violence prior to UN involvement in the war in Haiti would be relevant to defending the UN presence there.  Also, statements about people being shot, without any info on whether they were hit by stray bullets or executed at point blank range, or even who shot them, is of limited value.  No conclusions can be drawn from such statements. [[User:StuRat|StuRat]] 23:45, 10 August 2005 (UTC)

I have added a dispute tag in refrence to this discussion.  I will come back and clean up some of this pov. [[User:Daniel J. Leivick|Daniel J. Leivick]] 22:09, 5 January 2007 (UTC)

== Supplement ==

There has been a recent (July 28, 2005) request by the UN force commander in Haiti for personnel trained for operations in densely populated slum areas to reduce civilian casualties.

: do you have a reference for this? Macho Philipovich 17:03, 20 October 2005 (UTC)</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
