  <page>
    <title>Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Floating Bellhop</title>
    <id>2425015</id>
    <revision>
      <id>50208868</id>
      <timestamp>2006-04-26T04:58:03Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Cydebot</username>
        <id>1215485</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor />
      <comment>Robot - Removing extraneous links to old VfD templates.</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve">&lt;div class=&quot;boilerplate metadata vfd&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #F3F9FF; margin: 0 auto; padding: 0 10px 0 10px; border: 1px solid #AAAAAA;&quot;&gt;
This page is an archive of the proposed deletion of the article below.  Further comments should be made on the appropriate discussion page (such as the article's talk page or on a Votes for Undeletion nomination).  No further edits should be made to this page.  
&lt;!--
Note:  If you are seeing this page as a result of an attempt to re-nominate an article for deletion, you must manually edit the VfD nomination links in order to create a new discussion page using the name format of [[Wikipedia:Votes for deletion/PAGENAME (2nd nomination)]].  When you create the new discussion page, please provide a link to this old discussion in your nomination. --&gt;

The result of the debate was '''Delete'''. --[[User:Ryan Delaney|Ryan Delaney]] [[User talk:malathion|&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;talk&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;]] 18:04, 20 August 2005 (UTC)
===[[Floating Bellhop]]===
:''Completing a nomination from July 20. Tagging edit summary was: «could not find any other reference anywhere; seems fake».'''No vote'''.'' [[User:Nabla|Nabla]] 23:46:54, 2005-08-10 (UTC)
*'''Delete''' or '''weak merge'''.  I was about to call it a hoax too, but I found one reference on Google groups from 1996.  Certainly doesn't seem like a common term. [[User:Starblind|Andrew Lenahan - &lt;FONT COLOR=&quot;#FF0000&quot;&gt;St&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT COLOR=&quot;#FF5500&quot;&gt;ar&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT COLOR=&quot;#FF8000&quot;&gt;bli&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;FONT COLOR=&quot;#FFC000&quot;&gt;nd&lt;/FONT&gt;]] 00:05, August 11, 2005 (UTC)
*'''Delete''', slang definition. Hi Nabla. I think starting a VfD counts as a vote for deletion itself. Furthermore, you could have done a bit of research yourself and cast a vote. It seems strange to reopen a VfD creating more work for everyone. [[User:Sdedeo|Sdedeo]] 00:24, 11 August 2005 (UTC)
**I did not start nor reopen a VfD. I [http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Floating_Bellhop&amp;action=history found a VfD tag with no discussion page] and not listed here, so I simply completed someone else's nomination. I think that not voting is not unusual in those cases, although sometimes I do also vote. [[User:Nabla|Nabla]] 00:48:15, 2005-08-11 (UTC)
***Ah, sorry, misunderstood you. I think you did the right thing. [[User:Sdedeo|Sdedeo]] 00:55, 11 August 2005 (UTC)
****No problem. Thanks. [[User:Nabla|Nabla]] 12:55:12, 2005-08-11 (UTC)

:''The above discussion is preserved as an archive of the debate.  &lt;font color=red&gt;'''Please do not modify it.'''&lt;/font&gt; Subsequent comments should be made on the appropriate discussion page (such as the article's talk page or in an [[Wikipedia:Votes for undeletion|undeletion request]]). No further edits should be made to this page.&lt;/div&gt;</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
